Christopher Allen

Senior Full-Stack Web & Web3 Engineer

Breitenstrasse 109, Basel | superchrisallen@gmail.com | +41 33 575 2950

About

Experienced full-stack web engineer with over 9 years of experience working with a variety of technologies – over half of that working remotely. I have extensive knowledge of front-end JavaScript and browser APIs as well as significant experience with popular frameworks and libraries like React and Vue.js. My deep full-stack experience includes Node.js Python/Django and PHP/Laravel.

Education

Bachelor's Degree | Aalto University | 2010 - 2014

- · Major: Computer Science
- · Studied AI/ML and Web Development area
- · Researched ML-translation engine with corpus database written by Java and Python
- · Rebuilt web application for school community platform

Experience

Senior Front-End Engineer | Ncrypted Technologies | Aug 2019 - Current

- Took part in many front-end applications' development using React, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js,
 Angular TypeScript, GraphQL, Material UI and AWS Amplify.
- Took ownership of certain, particular modules of the projects (e.g., admin part of machine-marketing app).
- · Built common basic components and managed atomic UI components in **Storybook**.
- Built and published using **Babel** and **NPM** common components to **NPM** registry for micro-frontend implementation.
- Integrated 3rd party service **Google Analytics** to analyze users' activities on the system.
- · Translated **Figma** UI designs into pixel-perfect and well-organized pages.
- Implemented client-side data transformations to map, filter, reduce, etc. large datasets for display in interactive SVG charts using **D3.js.**
- Developed unit & e2e tests and component snapshot tests using Jest, @react/testing-library and Cypress.
- Increased the number of clients by 29% with the integration of i18n into the customer-facing application.
- · Created fully-responsive custom **React Data Table**s for all mobile devices.
- · Did a peer code review and mentored other junior members in the team.
- Utilized Skills: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Next.js, GraphQL, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, D3.js, Node.js, Google Analytics, Figma, Jest, @react/testing-library, Cypress, Storybook, AWS Amplify, Docker, Git, Jira.

Full-Stack Developer | **Evernote** | Jan 2016 – Jul 2019

- Redesigned the project architecture by micro-frontend and mid-tier microservices in React, Vue.js and Node.js.
- Took ownership of development of a unified rich text editor that runs on mobile, desktop and web for 200+ million users.
- Built scalable & robust **RESTful API**s and **GraphQL API**s to fetch data from the server using **Django Rest Framework** and integrated them into the front-end application.
- Built architecture for e2e test in the front-end application and increased test-coverage up to 75% using **Jest**, **@react/testing-library** and **Cypress**.
- · Utilized Skills: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue.js, Node.js, Python, Django, GraphQL, RESTful APIs, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Figma, AJAX, Firebase, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Git, Docker, Slack, Jira

Full-Stack Developer | **SMARTrms, Inc** | Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

- · Learned the basic knowledge and skills for web development.
- · Helped a variety of startup companies to launch their MVP successfully.
- · Took responsibilities for UI and coding individual programs from specific requirements.
- · Created semantic pages and mocked up static pages using **Bootstrap** UI framework
- · Mainly worked with **PHP/Laravel** to build MVP of an e-commerce platform.
- · Migrated legacy **jQuery** version code to **Angular** version.
- · Utilized Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Angular, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, PHP, Laravel and MySQL.

Skills (Years of Experience)

· HTML / CSS (9)	· Angular (2)	· PHP (3)	· Chakra UI (1)
· JavaScript (8)	· Node.js (5)	· Laravel (3)	· Jest (4)
· TypeScript (5)	· Express.js (4)	· Ruby (2)	· Mocha (3)
· React (6)	· Nest.js (2)	· Ruby On Rails (2)	· Cypress (3)
· Next.js (4)	· Python (3)	· GoLang (2)	· AWS (3)
· React Native (3)	· Django (3)	· Tailwind CSS (3)	· Docker (3)
· Vue.js (3)	· FastAPI (2)	· Material UI (3)	· Kubernetes (2)